A Guide to the Governor James Wood Executive Papers, 1796-1799
Library of Virginia
Other noteworthy items include: proceedings of a meeting of the President & Vice-President electors from Benjamin Temple (1796 Dec. 7); certificate of the oaths administered to Meriwether Jones & John Pendleton as Privy Councilors (1796 Dec. 7); certificate of the oath administered to James Wood as Governor (1796 Dec. 7); certificate of the oath taken by John Mayo as Privy Councilor (1796 Dec. 28); bond of William Price & John Harvie to record all grants, plats, & certificates of survey in the Land Office (1797 Jan. 30); certificate of election for Thomas Evans as a member of the U.S. House of Representatives for York District (1797 March 27); order for a warrant from the Auditor for the Lunatic Hospital in Williamsburg (1797 April 21); proclamation by Governor Wood regarding a reward for the capture of William Compton, alias Smith, convicted of murder (1797 May 18); articles of agreement between the Governor & James Swan of Boston to furnish 4,000 stand of arms for Virginia (1797 May N.D., 1798 Jan. 16, & 1798 April 10); certificate of Alexander McRae as a member of the Privy Council (1797 June 1); list of persons who qualified as citizens at Richmond District Court (1797 Aug. 31); bond of William Berkeley as Treasurer (1798 Jan. 12); report of the state of the Treasury at the death of Jaquelin Ambler (1798 Jan. 10); report of John Guerrant & Samuel McCraw on the Arsenal at Point of Fork and recommend the erection of a stockade (1798 Feb. 6); resolutions of the Massachusetts House of Representatives regarding an amendment to the Constitution concerning the eligibility of the President, Vice President, etc., as natural born citizens at the time of the Declaration (1798 June 28); proclamation calling the General Assembly into session on 3 September (1798 July 7); account of James Breckinridge for iron purchased by the Director of the Penitentiary Building (1798 Oct. 13); bond of William Berkeley as Treasurer (1799 Jan. 4); certificate of oath to John Allen & John White as Privy Councilors (1799 Jan. 24); statements of arms issued from the Public Arsenal to the militia since 1792 (1799 April 17 & June 22); election certificate of Henry Lee to the U.S. House of Representatives (1799 May 2); and bills of lading for shingles to the Penitentiary House (1799 Sept. 16).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of document with undated items arranged to the rear.
Contents List
- James Wood Executive Papers
- 1796
  - December
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 16-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1797
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 16-31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - February
    - 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 16-28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - March
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 16-31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - April
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 17-29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 17-31 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - June
    - 1-12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 19-27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - July
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 17-29 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - August
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - September
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 18-30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - October
    - 3-13 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 16-30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - November (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - December (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1798
  - January (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - February
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 16-28 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - March
    - 5-15 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - April (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - May
    - 2-15 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - June
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 18-30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - July
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 12-20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - August
    - 1-14 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 16-28 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - September (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - October
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 16-27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - November
    - 1-14 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 16-30 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - December (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1799
  - January
    - 1-19 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 21-29 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - February (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - March
    - 4-22 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 23-31 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 12-29 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - June
    - 3-15 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - July
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 16-24 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 25-31 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - August
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 11-25 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - 26-31 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - September (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - October
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 11-25 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 26-31 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - November
    - 4-10 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 12-20 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 22-30 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - December (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
- 1796
  - Dec. 6 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dec. 8 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Dec. 23 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- 1797
  - Jan. 16 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - March 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - April 20 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - May 20 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - May 30 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - June 3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - July 5 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - July 10 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - July 27 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - July 28 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Aug. 26 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Sept. 7 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sept. 10 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Nov. 11 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Dec. 7 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- 1798
  - Jan. 10 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Feb. 9 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - March 13 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - April 10 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - April 14 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - May 23 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - June 23 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - June 28 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - July 5 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - July 6 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - July 23 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - July 27 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - July 30 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Oct. 13 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Nov. 13 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Nov. 14 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Nov. 20 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Nov. 24 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Dec. 7 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Dec. 12 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Dec. 16 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- 1799
  - Jan. 5 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Jan. 24 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Jan. 24 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Feb. 10 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - April 4 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - April 19 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - June 9 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - July 16 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Aug. 27 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Sept. 7 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Nov. 9 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
- 1797
  - Jan. 5 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - March 7 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - March [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - April 20 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - May 25 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- 1798
  - March 5 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - April 12 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - July 15 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- 1799
  - April 17 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - June 22 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - June 30 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Aug. 12 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Aug. 12 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sept. 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Nov. 27 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Dec. 4 (Box 7, Folder 16)